

# **LUCAS ASSIS RODRIGUES**

**COMPUTER ENGINEER** 

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am computer engineering graduate enthusiastic about building gadgets and sharing knowledge. So I worked mentoring software engineering students, also did research with embedded systems. Currently taking the Master program at the Apple Developer Academy improving my mobile skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Universidade Federal de Itajubá

BA in Computer Engineering Graduated in Dec 2016

## The University of Texas at El Paso

Study Abroad, Electrical and Computer Engineering Aug 2015 - May 2016

## **Apple Developer Academy**

Master Class Expected graduation Jun 2018

## CONTACT

lucasassisro.github.io lucas.assis.ro@gmail.com +39 340 584 4170 | +55 35 98866 7871

#### **AWARDS**

- Second place overall at HackCU 2016 for B-Note.
- WWDC 2018 scholarship for ColorPiano playground.

#### **SKILLS**

- Java
- C#
- MSP430
- Hibernate
- Swift
- Arduino
- Git
- C/C++
- Particle Photon
- Sketch

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Universidade Federal de Itajubá

Teaching Assistant | Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

- Contributed to the strategic plan for software development.
- Worked with a team to design and develop a module for the university portal website.
- The API used for the website was Java Server Faces (JSF) communicating to a PostgreSQL database using Hibernate.

# Universidade Federal de Itajubá

IT Intern | Aug 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with students on one-by-one interactions and groups to help with assignments, reinforce the course concepts, and improve their overall performance.
- Assisted with grading and documenting the performance of the classes.
- Assisted the professor with the following courses: Object-Oriented Programming (C++), Applied Programming (Java).

## The University of Toledo

Research Intern | May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Worked to test, bug fix and improve the existing functionalities of an existing structural analysis software.
- Designed and developed new features.
- Coded in C++ using the MVC and OpenGL frameworks.

#### eWorld

Freelance Web Developer | Feb 2017 - Mar 2017

- Worked in both front-end and back-end development for the services provided by the company.
- Implemented the front-end functionalities in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Razor.
- Also implemented the back-end in C# using the Entity Framework to access the database.